um really high floor player. Um I
actually what's really intrigued
obviously he's look he's big, he's
tough, he's smart. Um he's he's a
finisher. He has unbelievable football
character, work ethic. I mean everything
from a culture standpoint. He fits that
that that's the easy part. But his
ability is the is is the stuff that I
mean he's athletic. He's a He's a good
athlete and you It's hard to find guys
that can move like that that are
finishers, which that that's what he is.
Um, and what's been interesting on him
is he probably has no idea. But we've
probably been watching Blake for about 3
years now and he literally has gotten
better every single year. And so that's
what that's what makes you really
excited about a player like that that
actually has a high floor, but he's
gotten better every year. And so coming
to this level with our offensive line
coach and our our ecosystem, um I don't
I don't see any reason why he won't
continue to get better.
>> A lot of the buzzwords that that you
guys talk about, grit, toughness,
finishing, that's what those are the
words that he used with us, too. When
you hear that, when you see that, what
does that mean in terms of just a
culture? Yeah, absolutely. Like uh you
know just you know um diving into his
interviews and just kind of hearing how
he answers question and his mindset and
his approach, how he was raised, how he
was brought up. I mean his morals. I
mean it's all about grit, earning it,
battling through adversity. I mean um it
was just it it just he just kept
checking the boxes and then he just kept
just rising and rising. But again, we
already knew that he was a good player,
but as we kind of got into this process
in the spring, um it just it just really
just didn't stop. So, we're really
really excited about him. And um I I
still think he's got a lot of upside.
>> You guys love his experience. I think
almost 3,800 snaps had 54 starts. That's
a lot of tape that you got to see.
>> How much do you like that with a with a
prospect company that you get that much
tape?
>> Yeah, he's uh he's he's he's been he's
been very durable. um you know uh thus
thus far. But you know, look, and that's
that's a that's that's a big- time
program. I mean, they they they played
some big-time football and he's gone
against some really good pass rushers in
his career. And so, um and how he's held
up versus the pass rushers that he's
faced throughout his career, going back
to previous year film, um it it it says
a lot. I tell you what, um when when you
think about Blake Miller, uh you sleep
easy. you know, you sleep very very good
at night and so um that's what that's
what gets us fired up. You
>> mentioned uh high se or high floor there
a couple times, Brad. Um also upside,
you know, when you look at his ceiling,
um you know, what what kind of player do
you think he could be develop into at
just 22 years old?
>> Yeah, I mean there's there's there's no
telling. I mean, look, he's he's going
to be a good starting tackle already.
like you you you got high conviction of
that. But there's no telling where this
can go because again I I just I can't
say it enough. Um you know me and our
our assistant GM Ray Agnar were talking
about just how much we've been watching
him and how better he's gotten. You
know, he's gotten stronger, his
technique's gotten better, his hands
have gotten better. And so um whether
it's it's run game, pass game, all all
of that, you know, um I think there's a
lot of growth left in him. And that's
hard to find a guy that's high. You
know, some guys, they have a really high
ceiling, but the floor is not as high
and so there's a little bit more
development. Look, these are all
rookies, so they're going to have their
lumps and all that. You know, we expect
that, but it's it's it's hard to find
guys that have the floor, still have
growth, cuz this guy, when you start
matching up his athleticism numbers and
all of that to these other tackles, I
mean, he's he he's right up in the mix.
So, um you know, we'll see how how high
it goes, but um I don't I don't have any
hesitation or any reservations that he's
going to continue to get better.
>> A couple times that you know, um you
were there at number 17, did you receive
any intriguing phone calls to
potentially trade down? And then I'm
just wondering also too, now that the
time has been reduced down to 8 minutes,
did that make it any more of a challenge
this year?
>> Uh that's a good question. Um no, did
not did not get calls. Um you know,
which I wasn't really surprised. Um, a
really I got I got a couple of calls um
uh a couple of days ago, but I just
didn't think that they were like really
just, you know, just the normal just
kind of feeling things out. But I did
not um get any calls
that No, we we we got one call. I'm
sorry. Yeah, let me take that back. We
we got one call um to possibly move
back, but um but that that that was it.
But in terms of the time, um I didn't
really feel a a big difference. Um, I
know that, you know, um, a lot of the
GMs were were pulled about that before
they enforced this this new rule and,
um, I think everybody felt good about
it. Um, you know, for the most part, a
lot of the trades, they're pretty much
kind of hammered out, um, you know,
within a few minutes at the most. Um and
especially a lot of first round trades
are kind of some range of parameters are
already kind of set before the draft
even starts so guys aren't scrambling
around and um so that's the trade
component cuz that's what you worry
about on the clock. But then also um
just who you're going to pick. So I
always feel like if you're staying true
to your board like we always do um it's
it's really it's really not hard. So I
was all on board and I think everybody
else was on board. So I I didn't feel a
difference. What can you say about the
overhaul of the offensive line now that
we're kind of towards the end of this
off season?
>> Yeah. Well, look, um, what what what
fires you up is we definitely got
younger and I I I think that's going to
be big uh going forward just for our
future and just the importance of of of
where you know the the importance of
that position as a whole and in in in
that unit. Um, look, when you start
getting in that in that in that cycle of
trying to find, you know, a younger
talented offensive tackle or, you know,
you could even throw guard, the center,
like those guys are hard to find. Um,
so, um, so really I would say the the
the the youth and look now these guys
can be grown and molded to what we
believe. uh they already have the
intangible qualities, but um but we're
really excited about the youth
injection. It kind of started last year
and then we just continued it.
>> How much did it free you up in your
process when you got a guy like Paneet
who if you drafted a left could stay
right, draft right, he could move to
left. How much did that free you guys
up?
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, that was um that that's
that that went all the way back to free
agency uh when we were you know looking
at Borum and you know just really all
the tackles in free agency and
especially we're already in the draft
prep process but that really is like
when you have a special talent like
Paneet you don't really feel handcuffed
because there I mean some guys they
don't make that transition as easily
just going from left to right or right
to left. um you know, a guy like Blake,
you know, I'm sure that if you ask him
to to do it, he he could do it just
because he's just that kind of athlete
and worker. Um but, you know, um but it
is it's just a lot of freedom. The fact
that um we would never felt like we were
in a box trying to find a right tackle
versus a left tackle. We just want to
get the best tackle. Brad, your your
offensive line powered this team's rise
way back in 2022, 2023, especially the
ability to run the ball consistently. Do
you feel like Blake's demeanor and and
play style can kind of reestablish the
way you guys want to play offensive
football or help reestablish it?
>> Oh, I I I I totally agree with that.
Well, because that was one of the things
that it was probably about um it it was
just it wasn't too long ago where um you
know just looking at all the tackles
again and just refreshing and just
looking at all the run blocking snaps of
all of them and Blake was just right up
there like among the top in terms of
just his sheer run block. I mean, this
guy's a a physical, gritty, phys I mean,
he's a finisher. He's a finisher. He's
trying to finish all the time. And when
you get into the interview process with
him, he talks about that, how he prides
himself on that. Now, look, a lot of
tackles will say that because it sounds
good to say in an interview, but his
tape actually says that. So, there's
certain guys that, you know, they might
they might fit you, but, you know, they
won't try to strain to stay connected.
But, um, Miller, that's why he's he's
such a fit. I mean, I I thought that he
was one of the better run blocking
tackles in this draft. For sure.
>> Three years ago, you know, you watched
him for three years. What was you
remember the first moment he caught your
eye? What it was? Who he was?
>> Yeah, it was um so so it was it was a
year ago watching So it was what would
that be 24? Watching his 23 tape earlier
in the season and um the first thing I
did was was his urgency and athleticism.
that that was that was the first thing
that really kind of caught my eye. Um I
I thought he had some things that he
needed to work on from a strength
development standpoint, but you know, I
said so this is off of 23 tape. I was
like, man, like this guy gets stronger,
man. Like this this guy's a this guy's a
football player here. And sure enough,
24 came, it got better. 25 it was like
25 was to the point was like, yeah, no,
there's no issues here. So, um, so and
it's it's a testament to him and his and
his work ethic. So, you're not not
surprised cuz this guy's a a high
football character individual with game
or who you were watching.
>> I cannot I cannot it was so long ago,
Dave. I can't remember. But, um, but I
do remember I just wrote down, you know,
this this kid's a football player and I
was definitely hot on the guy. Um, but I
just knew that he had some things to
work on. So, um, but and I don't know if
he heard that from others or what he
needed to work on, but, um, he
definitely got better every single year.
And I I I don't see how that's going to
stop now.
>> It seemed like this first round pick is
pretty easy. Like you said, you've been
studying him so long. Now you guys got
second round, then no third round. Like
just an interesting situation you
haven't really been in since you've been
here. But just pick so spread apart.
Like how do you approach the rest of
this draft? I mean, is it just more
studying? season like just it seemed
like yall just in a different position
with
>> Yeah. Um you know, we'll we'll go back
and look at it and get a fresh stack and
just kind of see, you know, um do we do
we have enough players? Do we feel
comfortable uh staying at 50 or, you
know, does it look like it's not enough?
And do we do we need to move back just
to reach our cluster or do we feel bad?
we've already kind of gone through that
um process already before the draft
started, but uh obviously, you know, you
never know till you see who's left. So,
we'll uh definitely go back, see what's
left, and then we'll kind of see. But,
you know, um if if we feel about if we
feel good about the cluster that's
there, you know, or that might be there,
then um we'll just go and pick the best
football player.
told a story that last
>> Blake told a story at the comline about
delaying uh I think it's going to his
junior year and delaying wrist surgery
so he could be out there for spring
football with his teammates. I'm sure
you heard that. Curious your thoughts on
that and what does that say about him as
a person as football?
>> Not surprised. Not surprised. I mean
even that that that's a great story. Um
that's that's what he's all about.
Again, that's that's why he's such a fit
here. Um but you know even um him
deciding know he was a left tackle in
high school and so um just kind of
hearing about why he went to right
tackle and he literally just said you
know man the line was shorter for the
right tackle spot so I just jumped in
the right tackle spot cuz I just wanted
to play and so that's just this this
guy's a this guy's a real football
player and um you know all the games and
starts and snaps and just all the uh the
durability that he's he's he's displayed
played. Um I just going to fit right in
here.
>> There was the uh the run on tackles 9 10
11. I know you were drafting the player,
not the position, but when those tackles
started coming off the board, you knew
you wanted Blake. Was there any part of
you that that kind of considered trading
up or was itching to trade up to go get
him?
>> We did. We did. Yeah. Yeah, we did. Um,
you know, look, um, we, you know, we we
we talk to teams, um, you know,
up, you know, way up and we kind of talk
about and try to see if we can be at
peace with what the capital is that
you'd have to expend. But, um, but yeah,
we we we definitely explored strongly
about trading up and then just kind of
seeing how it started to fall. Um,
probably about when we got to about
probably at right after LA took the
quarterback. Um I felt pretty good that
um that we might be able to just get
Blake cuz the other thing is that
there's just a little scare of okay I
felt like from the outside looking in we
had this big like tackle target on our
back. So if a team behind us was in the
tackle market then they might want to
jump us as well. So we we we definitely
explored that, but right right about 14,
I felt pretty good that we would be able
to um keep our assets and and still land
Blake.
>> Brad, when you say that he plays with
urgency, how do you see urgency in an
offensive lineman? Like what does it
look like to you on on tape?
>> Yeah, just a guy that will come off the
ball, especially like in the run game,
you know, when he gets that initial fit,
he's going to continue to strain through
the whistle. um he's not he's not
peeking back and seeing where the ball
is. He knows what his assignment is and
he's going to try and finish and bury
that guy. Um and really the same thing
in as a pass blocker. You know, a lot of
times defensive ends, you know, they can
rush you, but then depending on what the
quarterback does, if the quarterback
bails out of the back or flushes and and
goes up, you know, defensive ends can
retrace and then just get a sack because
the tackle just let him go. That's not
how Blake plays. Like when he feels that
retrace from that rusher, he chases the
retrace just again just to stay in
strain and just try to work to finish.
And it's for th those big guys, it's
hard to stay connected to those athletic
guys. But uh again, I think that was one
of the more in my opinion, I thought
that was one of the more underrated
things about Blake was his athleticism.
Thanks,
>> guys. All right. Thank you. Heat. Heat.
N.
Heat. Hey, heat. Hey, heat.